<story-context id="{bmad_folder}/bmm/workflows/4-implementation/story-context/template" v="1.0">
  <metadata>
    <epicId>3</epicId>
    <storyId>1</storyId>
    <title>Minimalist User Interface</title>
    <status>drafted</status>
    <generatedAt>fredag 12. desember 2025</generatedAt>
    <generator>BMAD Story Context Workflow</generator>
    <sourceStoryPath>docs/sprint-artifacts/3-1-minimalist-user-interface.md</sourceStoryPath>
  </metadata>

  <story>
    <asA>a user</asA>
    <iWant>to interact with a clean, minimal, and intuitive user interface</iWant>
    <soThat>I can focus on my tasks without distractions</soThat>
    <tasks>
- [ ] **Task 1: Apply Core Visual Theme (AC 1.1, 1.2)**
  - [ ] Configure Tailwind CSS to implement the "Refined Focus" color theme from the UX Design Specification.
  - [ ] Ensure the neutral palette and specified action colors are used for all base components (`body`, `headings`, `buttons`, `inputs`).
  - [ ] Apply the principles of hyper-minimalism and calm aesthetics to the "Proactive Dashboard" and "Focused Task View" layouts.

- [ ] **Task 2: Implement Responsive Layouts (AC 1.3)**
  - [ ] Use Tailwind's responsive breakpoints (`sm`, `md`, `lg`, `xl`) to adapt the layout for different screen sizes.
  - [ ] Verify that the main UI elements, particularly the dashboard widgets, reflow correctly from a single column on mobile to a grid on desktop, as defined in the UX spec.

- [ ] **Task 3: Ensure Component Styling Consistency (AC 1.2)**
    - [ ] Review all existing `shadcn/ui` components to ensure they correctly inherit and apply the "Refined Focus" theme.
    - [ ] Verify that visual feedback on interaction (hover, focus, click) is subtle and non-distracting.
    </tasks>
  </story>

  <acceptanceCriteria>
1.  **Aesthetic and Layout:**
    1.1. The "Proactive Dashboard" and "Focused Task View" layouts adhere to the principles of hyper-minimalism and calm aesthetics defined in the UX Design Specification.
    1.2. The application's "Refined Focus" theme is correctly applied, using the specified neutral palette and action colors for all UI elements.
2.  **Responsiveness:**
    2.1. The UI layout adapts responsively from mobile to desktop screen sizes, with elements reflowing as defined in the UX spec.
  </acceptanceCriteria>

  <artifacts>
    <docs>
      <doc>
        <path>docs/ux-design-specification.md</path>
        <title>ibe160 UX Design Specification</title>
        <section>2. Visual Design - "Refined Focus" Theme</section>
        <snippet>Defines the color palette, typography, and spacing for the application's minimalist aesthetic.</snippet>
      </doc>
       <doc>
        <path>docs/ux-design-specification.md</path>
        <title>ibe160 UX Design Specification</title>
        <section>3. Layout &amp; Responsiveness</section>
        <snippet>Provides the detailed specifications for the responsive grid and how components should reflow across different breakpoints.</snippet>
      </doc>
    </docs>
    <code>
      <file>
        <path>nextjs-frontend/tailwind.config.js</path>
        <description>The primary configuration file for defining the color theme and other Tailwind CSS settings.</description>
      </file>
      <file>
        <path>nextjs-frontend/src/app/globals.css</path>
        <description>Global stylesheet where base styles and theme variables are applied.</description>
      </file>
    </code>
    <dependencies>
        <ecosystem name="Node.js / Frontend">
            <package name="tailwindcss" />
            <package name="shadcn/ui" />
        </ecosystem>
    </dependencies>
  </artifacts>

  <constraints>
- All styling must be done using Tailwind CSS utility classes or `globals.css` for base styles; no other CSS methodologies should be introduced.
- The implementation must strictly follow the visual and layout specifications in the UX Design Specification document.
</constraints>
  <interfaces></interfaces>
  <tests>
    <ideas>
    - Visual regression testing (e.g., using Playwright's screenshot capabilities) to compare the implemented UI against design mockups at various breakpoints.
    - Manual testing across different browsers and devices to verify responsive behavior.
    - E2E tests that navigate the application and assert that key elements are visible and correctly styled.
  </ideas>
  </tests>
</story-context>